{"topics":[{"topic":"Android"},{"topic":"Titanium"},{"topic":"Phonegap"}],"interview-questions":{"Android":[{"question":"What is Android?","answer":"Android is an open-source, linux-based operating system that is used in mobiles, tablets, televisions, watches etc"},{"question":"What are the code names of Android?","answer":"• Alpha,\n\n• Beta, \n\n• Cupcake, \n\n• Donut, \n\n• Eclair, \n\n• Froyo, \n\n• Gingerbread, \n\n• Honycomb, \n\n• Ice Cream Sandwitch, \n\n• Jelly Bean, \n\n• Kitkat, \n\n• Lollipop"},{"question":"What is AVD?","answer":"AVD Stand for Android Virtual Device (emulator). The Android SDK includes a mobile device emulator - a virtual mobile device that runs on your computer."},{"question":"What is an Activity?","answer":"An Activity is a single, focused thing that the user can do. Whenever the user clicks on GUI the next Activity will be start and new GUI set base on coding."},{"question":"What is Intent?","answer":"An Intent is basically a message to say you did or want something to happen. Depending on the intent, apps or the OS might be listening for it and will react accordingly."},{"question":"Types of Intent?","answer":"• Implicit Intent\n\n• Explicit Intent"},{"question":"How to Start Another Activity?","answer":"Intent i = new Intent(getApplicationContext(), Activity2.class); \nstartActivity(i);"},{"question":"What are the Main Components of an Android application?","answer":"Activities - They dictate the UI and handle the user interaction to the smartphone screen. \n\nServices - They handle background processing associated with an application. \n\nBroadcast Receivers - They handle communication between Android OS and applications. \n\nContent Providers - They handle data and database management issues."},{"question":"Inventors of android?","answer":"Andy Rubin, Rich Miner, Nick Sears"},{"question":"What is an Explicit Intent?","answer":"Explicit intent specifies the particular activity that should respond to the intent. They are used for application internal messages."},{"question":"What is an Implicit Intent?","answer":"In case of Implicit Intent, an intent is just declared. It is for the platform to find an activity that can respond to it."},{"question":"What do intent filters do?","answer":"There can be more than one intents, depending on the services and activities that are going to use them. Each component needs to tell which intents they want to respond to. Intent filters filter out the intents that these components are willing to respond to."}],"Titanium":[{"question":"Difference between heavyweight window and lightweight window?","answer":"• Heavy weight window is associate with new android activity. \n• Lightweight window is a full view which runs on current android activity"},{"question":"What is Closure","answer":"Closure is an inner function has access to variables in outer function. it has three scope chain."},{"question":"Difference between TI.UI.SIZE and FILL","answer":"TI.UI.SIZE : It will expand the height and width automatically Ti.ui,fill: It will occupy height and width of the parent view"}],"Phonegap":[{"question":"Explain what PhoneGap is and why to use it?","answer":"PhoneGap is an open source framework, which enables you to develop applications for mobile devices by using web technologies like CSS3, JavaScript and HTML5 instead of using Java for Android, C# for windows phone devices and Objective C or Swift for iOS. It uses the native project format for each platform."},{"question":"Explain how do you architect PhoneGap applications?","answer":"PhoneGap applications can be architect, in the same way, like other mobile web services. The main difference is that the initial HTML assets are available locally, instead of a remote server"},{"question":"Mention what are the storage option does PhoneGap can access?","answer":"• Memory-store.js (MemoryStore) \n\n• Is-store.js (LocalStorageStore) \n\n• Websql-store.js (WebSqlStore)"},{"question":"Explain what are the limitation of PhoneGap?","answer":"• Data processing : is slow when compared to javascript or native language. \n\n• Back-ground processing : Multi-thread is not possible and hence does not support background processing. \n\n• Advanced graphics:  Apps that use advanced graphics can be accessed explicitly by third party libraries, which can be best done natively. \n\n• Complex business logic: Number of complex business apps can be accessed better with native code."},{"question":"List out some of the PhoneGap API?","answer":"Some of the PhoneGap API are: \n\n• Accelerometer \n\n• Camera \n\n• Capture \n\n• Compass \n\n• Connection \n\n• Contacts \n\n• Device \n\n• Geo-location"},{"question":"List out some of the PhoneGap events?","answer":"Some of the PhoneGap events include: \n\n• Pause \n\n• Resume \n\n• Deviceready \n\n• Offline \n\n• Endcallbutton \n\n• Volumedownbutton  \n\n• online \n\n• StartCallbutton \n\n• Volumeupbutton \n\n• Batterystatus \n\n• BatteryCritical"},{"question":"Mention what is the difference between PhoneGap and PhoneGap Build?","answer":"• PhoneGap: It is a framework for mobile application development, built upon the open source Apache Cordova project. It permits you to write an app once with CSS, JavaScript, HTML and then deploys it to a broad range of mobile devices without losing the features of a native app. \n\n• PhoneGap Build: It is a cloud-based service built on top of the PhoneGap framework."},{"question":"Explain how do you architect PhoneGap applications?","answer":"PhoneGap applications can be architect, in the same way, like other mobile web services. The main difference is that the initial HTML assets are available locally, instead of a remote server.  The PhoneGap application loads the initial HTML which can request resources from a server or from the local environment.  PhoneGap also supports the single page web experienced model."},{"question":"What is Plist file in IOS development?","answer":"Property lists are a way of structuring arbitrary data and accessing it at run-time. An information property list is a specialized type of property list that contains configuration data for a bundle. The keys and values in the file describe the various behaviors and configuration options you want applied to your bundle. Xcode typically creates an information property list file for any bundle-based projects automatically and configures an initial set of keys and values with appropriate default values. You can edit the file to add any keys and values that are appropriate for your project or change the default values of existing keys."},{"question":"What is the difference between ChildBrowser and InAppBrowser in PhoneGap?","answer":"• ChildBrowser is a plugin is used to open a page that is external to the host application. \n\n• InAppBrowser is a Phonegap ApI which is used to open a window page when calling windows.open()."},{"question":"Advantages of PhoneGap","answer":"• One codebase can be maintained for multiple platforms \n\n• Reuse existing web developer skills \n\n• Faster development \n\n• Based on open standards"}]}}